Guide to the Oliver F. Atkins photograph collection, 1943-1975
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 5: Oversize, 1943-1971; (12 boxes)
  - Prophet Jones minus jewels but now dressed in white mink, 1955 (Oversize 7, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified white bearded officer (Indian?) in uniform inspecting line of young men (recruits perhaps), 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 9)
    13 1/8" x 8 1/2"
  - Portrait of young girl with scarification on face and neck, a sign of beauty, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 10)
    16" x 10 1/4"
  - Portrait of young African woman with dangling earrings and hair in cornrows, another young woman in background wearing turban, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 11)
  - Portrait of woman with scars on face wearing a turban which is imaginatively arranged in complicated folds, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 12)
    13 1/4" x 8 1/4"
  - Portrait of children in native dress wearing jewelry, some with scars, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 13)
  - Portrait of very young children clinging to each other, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 14)
    13" x 8 3/4"
  - Portrait of very young children clinging to each other, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 15)
  - Portrait of a young child carrying an even younger child piggyback, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 16)
    13" x 9"
  - Four very young children in ragged native dress in front of hut, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 17)
  - Mother with four children in front of hut, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 18)
  - Portrait of young African man wearing white turban with scarification on face, 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 19)
  - Two elderly men weaving baskets, "Algerians - Arabs in side street in Algiers" (Newspaper caption), 1960s (Oversize 7, Folder 20)
  - Group washing cloth or clothing by river, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
  - Soldiers instructing women dressed in saris on the use of rifles, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
  - Two women riding donkeys, one holding a child, palm trees in the background, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 3)
    13 1/2" x 8 1/4"
  - Two men working with a team of cattle are drawing water for irrigation, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 4)
    8 1/2" x 13 1/4"
  - Camel used in a go-round to draw water, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 5)
  - Two men with humpback cattle appear to be fertilizing lawn of massive building with a number of elegant Indians in background looking on, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 6)
    10 3/8" x 13 1/8"
  - Group of women in native dress wearing gold jewelry carrying huge vessels on their heads, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 7)
    12 3/4" x 10 1/2"
  - Bustling city street, a mix of various animals and people of all ages, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 8)
    12 7/8" x 10"
  - Street scene with people sleeping on sidewalk using rags and mats as covers, one sleeper has a pan for pillow, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 9)
  - Young boy with pots and shards of vessels in a pile in street, other Indians in various activities in background, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 10)
    13 3/8" x 8 1/8"
  - Woman with four children squatting in middle of street appear to be eating from several pots placed on street, sheep being herded down street in background, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 11)
  - Four children around cooking stove with woman standing by, clothes are hung on an iron fence surrounding large stone building, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 12)
  - Three woman, one holding child over hip, at an open air butcher shop, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 13)
  - Downtown scene with sacred cows lolling on street car platform, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 14)
    7 3/8" x 13 3/8"
  - Building construction with native women carrying bricks on their heads, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 15)
    13 1/2" x 8 3/4"
  - Building construction with native women carrying bricks on their heads, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 16)
  - City street scene with young boy washing dishes in a puddle in street, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 17)
  - Man lying on ledge of building with iron grates behind, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 18)
    13 1/2" x 10 5/8"
  - View of shanty village with young children playing in the background, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 19)
  - View of shanty village with young children playing in the background, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 20)
  - Shanty village with many children of all ages, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 21)
  - Woman squatting at a cooking oven wearing gold jewelry with small child in background, a tent covered with burlap and rags in background, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 22)
    13 1/4" x 9 1/4"
  - Cattle moving through shanty village, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 23)
    12 7/8" x 9 3/4"
  - Old man in wagon, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 24)
  - Portrait of old man, his head wrapped in gauze, wears an elaborate robe, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 25)
    13 3/8" x 8 7/8
  - Scene in Middle East of sheep being driven through busy street, vendors line street, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 26)
  - Street scene in Calcutta with people sleeping on sidewalks, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 27)
  - Street scene in Calcutta with a mother and her three children having their meal from pots placed on sidewalk beside them, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 28)
  - "India, 1962 - November. College girls getting rifle training during Chinese attack emergency." (Newspaper caption) (Oversize 9, Folder 29)
  - Picturesque India scene somewhere in the countryside with man and his donkey near lake surrounded by hills in background, 1950s (Oversize 9, Folder 30)
  - Picture of fish breaking water, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 1)
  - Fire in pine forest, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 2)
    10 1/4" x 12 3/4"
  - A couple of "Jitterbugs" dancing, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 3)
    13 1/4" x 11"
  - Photograph of "Jitterbugs", 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 4)
  - Group of golfers walking in rain with umbrellas, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 5)
  - Scene at soda fountain with two young women enjoying soda, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 6)
  - Scene of front of newsstand with three men reading a racing paper, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 7)
  - Trash collectors looking over an overcoat and pair of boots discarded in trash, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 8)
    additional notes by Atkins on back of photograph; 10 1/2" x 13 1/4"
  - Workmen at the Kenilworth dump looking over some trash, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 9)
  - Photograph of six hands holding up dollar bills, one bill burning, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 10)
    10 3/8" x 12 7/8"
  - Night scene along the Potomac River with man sitting on folding chair watching three propped-up fishing poles with lines in the water and bridge lights reflected in the river, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 11)
  - Portrait of an elderly black man wearing an apron, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 12)
  - Two miners shovelling coal in mine, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 13)
  - Miner in coal mine holding lamp, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 14)
  - Miner lying on coal conveyor belt, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 15)
  - Two miners working in mine, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 16)
  - Worker making wood posts, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 17)
    10 1/2" x 13 1/4"
  - Workers loading horse drawn wagon with burlap sacks of feed, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 18)
  - Worker at Brown-Forman Distilling Co. in Kentucky, 1950s (Oversize 10, Folder 19)
  - Closeup scene on National Mall in Washington, D.C. with huge crowd around the Reflecting Pool, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 1)
    13 1/2" x 19 5/8"
  - Protesters in Reflecting Pool, National Mall, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 2)
  - Protesters with placards demonstrating near the White House, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 3)
  - Demonstrators carrying placards with read "UAW says Jobs and Freedom for every American" and "We March for Effective Civil Rights Law Now" and others, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 4)
  - Demonstrators shown close up, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 5)
    13 1/4" x 10 1/8"
  - Group of young people pictured from the back, one young man with head shaved and "PEACE NOW!" spelled out on the back of his head, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 6)
  - Scene at "Resurrection City" during protest in 1968 (Oversize 11, Folder 7)
  - Plywood shacks and muddy ground in "Resurrection City" with the Washington Monument in the background, 1968 (Oversize 11, Folder 8)
    9 1/2" x 13 3/8"
  - Three people in "Resurrection City" walking carefully over muddy ground, 1968 (Oversize 11, Folder 9)
  - Washington Monument with fireworks reflected in water, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 10)
    12 3/4" x 9 1/4"
  - Washington Monument framed by trees in silhouette with interesting cloud patterning as background, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 11)
    9" x 11 7/8"
  - Statue of Abraham Lincoln seen through columns in the Lincoln Memorial, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 12)
    13 1/4" x 9 1/8"
  - Dome of U.S. Capitol building during reconstruction with scaffolding surrounding the upper part of dome, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 13)
    13" x 10 5/8"
  - Department of Justice photographed with a bullet eye lens with some figures on the steps, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 14)
    13 3/8" x 10 1/4"
  - Department of Justice photographed with a bullet eye lens with some figures on the steps, cut in a circle, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 15)
    9 1/4" diameter
  - Street scene on F Street, N.W. in Washington, D.C., 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 16)
  - Trinity Church at the end of Wall Street in New York City, 1960s (Oversize 11, Folder 17)
    13 1/8" x 9 3/8"
  - Richard M. Nixon sitting on wicker chair on White House lawn, September 25, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 1)
  - Richard M. Nixon sitting at desk in Oval Office, September 25, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 2)
  - Richard M. Nixon and two other men sitting at desk in Oval Office with photograph of the Earth from the Moon hanging on the wall, March 13, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 3)
  - Richard M. Nixon talking with three men at desk in Oval Office, March 13, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 4)
  - Richard M. Nixon closeup profile portrait, February 19, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 5)
  - Richard M. Nixon drinking from a coffee cup, February 19, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 6)
  - Richard M. Nixon closeup, February 19, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 7)
  - Henry Kissinger portrait, February 4, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 8)
  - Richard M. Nixon smiling, February 2, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 9)
  - Richard M. Nixon, February 2, 1970 (Oversize 12, Folder 10)
  - Richard M. Nixon portrait, 1968 (Oversize 12, Folder 11)
  - Nixon family dinner with Richard M. Nixon, Pat Nixon, Tricia Nixon, Julie Nixon Eisenhower, David Eisenhower, 1970-1971 (Oversize 12, Folder 12)
    color
  - Nixon family dinner with Richard M. Nixon, Pat Nixon, Tricia Nixon, Julie Nixon Eisenhower, David Eisenhower, 1970-1971 (Oversize 12, Folder 13)
  - Nixon portrait, 1970-1971 (Oversize 12, Folder 14)
  - Portrait of Nixon family, Julie Nixon and Tricia Nixon as little girls, with Richard M. Nixon and Pat Nixon, 1952 (Oversize 12, Folder 15)
  - Richard M. Nixon with group of men and photographer in front of airplane, 1953-1961 (Oversize 12, Folder 16)
  - Smiling portrait of Richard M. Nixon, 1953-1961 (Oversize 12, Folder 17)